Guide to the East Asia collection, 1877-1923
Department of Special Collections
East Asia collection,
1877-1923
Special Collections M0139
Sheppard, Eli T.
1 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
BIOGRAPHY
Eli T. Sheppard, whose papers form a large portion of this collection, was a diplomat and lawyer; American consul at Tientsin, China (1871-1876) and advisor in international law to Japanese foreign office (1876-1880).
SCOPE AND CONTENT
Material relating to the Orient (primarily Japan), its philosophy, art, way of life, history, government, etc. Includes mss. of books, letters, memos and reports. The typescripts of the Papers of Eli T. Sheppard form the bulk of the material. The Warden volume is a general history of consular establishments which belonged to Mr. Sheppard, ca. 1877 - 1923.
CONTAINER LIST
- CHENG, CHE YU 1911 - (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Proverbial Philosophy, Chinese Proverbs and their Occidental Equivalents. Typescript with ms. corrections. Gift: Author.
- SHEPPARD, ELI T. (Legal Adviser to the Japanese Foreign Office, 1876 - 1881)(Ed. by P. J. Treat), PAPERS OF
  - #1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1. General Grant in the Orient, a typescript copy [by Payson J. Treat?]
      Gift of Payson J. Treat
    - 2. Calendar of Papers not Copied.
    - 3. List of Papers.
  - #2 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1. Regulations for the use of His Imperial Majesty's Consular Service.
    - 2. Memo for Mr. Ito. Light Houses and Light House Dues.
    - 3. 1877, May 16.Ltr. to Terashima Munenari re: privileges of war vessels.
    - 4. 1877, May 18.To Samashima re: naturalization.
    - 5. 1877, May 21.To Samashima re: naturalization.
    - 6. 1877, May 31.To Terashima Munenori re: light house dues.
    - 7. 1877, June 29.To Arinori Mori re: press laws.
    - 8. 1877, Aug. 2.To Samashima re; Report upon the Origin, Nature and History of Consular Jurisdiction.
    - 9. 1877, Sep. 6.To Samashima re: press laws.
    - 10. n.d.To the Several Foreign Ministers in Japan re: press laws.
    - 11. 1877, Sep. 12.To Tomeita re: collection of taxes from residents abroad.
    - 12. 1877, Oct. 1.To Foreign Representatives in Japan covering tariff of light dues.
    - 13. 1877, Oct. 4.Portion of draft of instructions to Japanese ministers re: treaties revarsion.
    - 14. 1877, Oct.To Consular Agent of Japan in Honolulu. Instructions.
    - 15. 1877, Nov. 12.To Arinori Mori re: revision of treaties.
    - 16. 1877, Dec. 10.Memo re: claim of Messers Grosser and Co.
    - 17. 1877, Dec. [11 or 19].Protion of df. of instructions to Japanese Minister to Great Britain.
    - 18. 1877, Dec. 24.Memo re: Crimes and limits of criminal jurisdiction of Consular Agents in Japan.
    - 19. [1877, Dec.]Df. of circular addressed to Western Powers
  - #3 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1. [1878], Jan. 13.Argument for treaty revision by Japanese student in diplomatic office.
    - 2. [1878, Oct.?].To Mr. Bingham. Acknowledges receipt of 1877 U.S. Diplomatic Correspondence.
    - 3. 1878, Mar. 12.To Sir Harry Parkes re: medicinal opium.
    - 4. 1878, Mar. 13.To Terashima re: medicinal opium.
    - 5. 1878, Mar. 22.To Miuamote Koichi re: quarantine regulations for war vessels.
    - 6. 1878, Apr. 11.To Minister for Foreign Affrs. re: Opinion of Wilkinson in Regina vs. Hartley; smuggling of opium.
    - 7. 1878, May 9.To Yoshida re: right of foreign merchants to trade beyond treaty limits.
    - 8. 1878, May 25.To Hanabusa Yoshimoto re: landing of British troops in Japan.
    - 9. 1878, May 31.To Judge Bingham re: Goodman ice case.
    - 10. [1878].To Judge Bingham re: Goodman ice case.
    - 11. 1878, June 14.To Terashima Munenori re: taxation of moveable property.
    - 12. [1878, July].To [Mr. Bingham] re: barque Valetta.
    - 13. 1878, Aug. 6.To Miyamoto re: sale of arms by a Portugese.
    - 14. [1878, Aug. 26].Quarantine Regulations.
    - 15. 1878, Sep. 25.To Sir Harry Parkes df. of dispatch from Foreign Minister re: quarantine regulations.
    - 16. 1878, Oct. 10.To [Mr. Bingham] re: Thomas Glass.
    - 17. 1878, Nov. 15.Memo on ltr. of Sir Harry Parkes of Oct. 31 re: quarantine laws.
    - 18. 1878, Nov. 29.To Shioda Sabaro re: actions in U.S. courts in Japan.
  - #4 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1. 1879, Mar. 18.To Arinori Mori opinion of Caleb Cushing re: most favored nation clause.
    - 2. 1879, Apr. 15.Osaki to Sheppard re: graveyards.
    - 3. 1879, Apr. 16.To Osaki re: graveyards.
    - 4. 1879, May 5.To Arinori Mori re: extraterritorial jurisdiction.
    - 5. 1879, May 19.To Arinori Mori re: extraterritorial jurisdiction.
    - 6. 1879, June.To Sir Harry Parkes re: treaty revision.
    - 7. 1879, July 3.To Sir Harry Parkes re: treaty revision from Von Brandt.
    - 8. 1879, Aug. 9.Robert Beadon. British Foreign Jurisdiction Act and Orders in Council.
    - 9. 1879, Aug. 21.Memo of Robert Beadon.
- SMITH, THOMAS C.
  - 1. The Agrarian Origins of Modern Japan. Typescript with ms. editing and corrections. Part I, Chapters 1 - 5. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 2. The Agrarian Origins of Modern Japan. Chapters 6 - 10, Part III. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 3. The Agrarian Origins of Modern Japan. Chapters 11 - 13. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 4. Notes (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - The Agricultural Revolution in Japan, 1600 - 1864;The Agrarian Background of Modernization. First draft copy. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - 5. Chapter 1: The Land System.
    - 6. Chapter 2: Agricultural Servants. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - 7. Chapter 3: Labor Services. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - 8. Chapter 4: Small Holdings. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - 9. Chapter 5: The Organization of Political Power. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - 10. Chapter 6: The Growth of the Market. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - 11. Chapter 7: Agricultural Technology. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - 12. Chapter 8: The Transformation of Labor. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - 13. Chapter 9: The Transformation of Nago into Tenants. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - 14. Chapter 10: Decline of the Cooperative Group (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - 15. Chapter 11: [Emergence of Class Conflict]. (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - 16. Chapter 12: Political Conflict. (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - 17. Chapter 13: Conclusion. (Box 2, Folder 22)
- WARDEN, DAVID BAILLIE (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - The Origin, Nature, Progress and Influence of Consular Establishments. Manuscript copy made under direction of Hamilton Fish for use of Eli T. Sheppard in organizing Consular Service of Japan in 1877.
- SOKEN KISHU (Box 3)
  - Estimation of Ornaments on Swords by Michitatsu G. Inaba. Handwritten translation by [Huggins?]. 1923, Jan.?.A.L.S. to H. C. Huggins from Yameto Ichihashi. Ptd. Pamphlet: Japanese Metallurgy; Part I - Gold and Silver and Their Alloys by W. Gowland.
- GREGORY, EDNA HOPE (MRS. HERBERT E.) (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - A typed manuscript entitled A Duck Hunt in Japan which took place on the occasion of the 1926 Pan Pacific Science Congress, with two photos showing Dr. [UNK] Lyman Wilbur. [UNK]
- KURODA, NAGAMICHI
  - A printed booklet Wild Duck Hunting at Haneda, Tokyo 1926,donated by Dr. Bailey Willis. Describes the same style of duck hunting with nets at the above manuscript.
- MOTOYAMA, HIKOICHI (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Draft of speech welcoming delegates to Instit. of Pacific relations conference, Nov. 14, 1927,at [UNK]